Mss.575.109.C67
American Philosophical Society
Genetics Collection, 1884-1971
Mss.575.109.C67
American Philosophical Society
1.5 Linear feet Ca. 1200 items, 1.5 linear feet
This miscellaneous collection relates to numerous topics in genetics: cattle breeding (especially the American Jersey Cattle Club), longevity, radiation, International Congress of Genetics (the 10th, 11th, and 13th), Gregor Mendel, aid for refugee scientists, and the records of the Genetics Society of America (1947-1974).
Ca. 1200 items (1.5 linear ft.).
Bateson, William, 1861-1926
Bridges, Calvin B. (Calvin Blackman), 1889-1938
Buzzati-Traverso, Adriano A.
Demerec, M., (Milislav), 1895-1966
Dempster, Everett R., (Everett Ross), 1903-
Gowen, John Whittemore, 1893-1967
Hollaender, Alexander, 1898-1986
Lederberg, Joshua
Muller, H. J., (Hermann Joseph), 1890-1967
Schindler, Alois
Stadler, Janice B., 1912-
Umaersus, Magnhild
Various authors
Virtanen, A. I., (Artturi Ilmari), 1895-1973
Box 1-2
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by Everett Dempster, John Gowen, Alexander Hollaender, Hugo Iltis, Joshua Lederberg, and Mrs. H. J. Muller, 1970-1974; initial accession, 08/31/1970.
Genetics Note
This collection contains materials which relate to the history of genetics.
Bateson, William N. Correspondence (2 items) 1905-1909
Bridges, Calvin B. Correspondence (1 item) 1937
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Focke, Wilhelm Olbers Correspondence (1 item) 1914
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Genetics Society of America Correspondence (57 items) 1947-1974
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Gowen, John Whittemore Manuscripts (3 items) n.d.
Hugo Iltis Papers -- International Congress of Genetics. Tenth Congress Records (6 folders) 1955-1958
Hugo Iltis Papers -- International Congress of Genetics. Thirteenth Congress Records (12 folders) 1971-1973
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Johannsen, Wilhelm Photographs (25 photographs, 2 letters) 1969
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Kerkis, Julius J. Manuscripts (1 item) 1935
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Lederberg, Joshua Correspondence (32 items) 1946-1957
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Mendel, Gregor Manuscripts (3 photocopies) n.d.
Hugo Iltis Papers -- Weismann, August Correspondence (1 item) 1906
Muller, Hermann Joseph Correspondence (4 items) 1946-1947
American Jersey Cattle Club.; Genetics Society of America.; Mendel, Gregor, 1822-1884; Biology--Research; Breeding.; Cattle -- Breeding.; Genetics -- Research.; Longevity -- Genetic aspects.; Political refugees.; Radiation -- Physiological effects.
- Selected Inventory from Genetics Subject Guide
  - Bateson, William N., 1905-1909; Correspondence ( 2 items )
    History of biology, especially genetics -- Mendel, Gregor; Publication
  - Bridges, Calvin B., 1937; Correspondence ( 1 item )
    Cytogenetics; Genetics -- Mutation rates
  - Hugo Iltis Papers
    - Focke, Wilhelm Olbers, 1914; Correspondence ( 1 item )
      Mendel, Gregor
    - Genetics Society of America, 1947-1974; Correspondence ( 57 items )
      Conferences and symposia; Displaced German scholars; Genetics Society of America; Political issues; Radiation genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
    - Gowen, John Whittemore, n.d.; Manuscripts ( 3 items )
      Genetics -- Cattle; Unpublished manuscripts, notes, etc.
    - International Congress of Genetics. Tenth Congress, 1955-1958; Records ( 6 folders )
      Conferences and symposia; International Congress of Genetics -- Tenth Congress; Publication -- International Congress of Genetics Proceedings
    - International Congress of Genetics. Thirteenth Congress, 1971-1973; Records ( 12 folders )
      Conferences and symposia; International Congress of Genetics -- Thirteenth Congress
    - Johannsen, Wilhelm, 1969; Photographs ( 25 photographs, 2 letters )
      Biographical and personal data; Photographs
    - Kerkis, Julius J., 1935; Manuscripts ( 1 item )
      Drosophila genetics
    - Lederberg, Joshua, 1946-1957; Correspondence ( 32 items )
      Bacterial genetics; Bacteriophage and viral genetics; Cold Spring Harbor Laboratory; Genetics; Human genetics; Molecular genetics
    - Mendel, Gregor, Manuscripts ( 3 photocopies )
    - Weismann, August, 1906; Correspondence ( 1 item )
  - Muller, Hermann Joseph, 1946-1947; Correspondence ( 4 items )
    Cytogenetics; Genetics of plants; Genetics Society of America -- Committee on Aid to Geneticists Abroad; International Congress of Genetics -- Sixth Congress; Requests for aid in finding positions; Russian politics and science; Russian politics and science -- Lysenko, Trofim Denisovich; Savicki, Wieczeslav; Scientific refugees; Solicitations for support or contribution